<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Pages on IDIA 640</title>
    <link>https://ub-idia640-2016.github.io/pages/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Pages on IDIA 640</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2016 Lisa D. Harper</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Sep 2016 10:15:13 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ub-idia640-2016.github.io/pages/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>github&#39;s invisible design</title>
      <link>https://ub-idia640-2016.github.io/pages/github-invisible-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Sep 2016 10:15:13 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ub-idia640-2016.github.io/pages/github-invisible-design/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the first week, I gave you a silly exercise centered on learning the basics of GitHub. Your goal was to create a markdown document on the topic of making toast, commit it to your repository, and inform me when that document was complete.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You are no doubt left with the question &amp;ldquo;why toast?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a teaser to the answer to this question, check out the following video from Tom Wujec.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://embed-ssl.ted.com/talks/tom_wujec_got_a_wicked_problem_first_tell_me_how_you_make_toast.html&#34; width=&#34;640&#34; height=&#34;360&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; scrolling=&#34;no&#34; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Based on what you may know about GitHub, can you see some parallels?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wujec makes the really interesting point that people intuitively know how to break down complex things into simple things. When you give people affordances that allow them to iterate more easily, they perform this task more easily.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Equally interesting is what happens in a group. Collaboration appears chaotic in the early stages, but stabilizes later. And in the process, many points-of-view are incorporated - even parallel and contradictory processes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is exactly what happens when groups collaborate in GitHub. It is designed for this. The difference is that the structure is only partly visible &amp;ndash; as a beginner, you may see processes exposed through browser-based interactions, but likely you struggle with understanding task structure under-the-hood. I know I did! Regardless, you are just making toast:
- Start with an idea about a problem to solve
- Create nodes (on branches)
- Refine &amp;amp; refine &amp;amp; refine
- Gain clarity as a group and solve the problem&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I find visual guides useful, when trying to see underlying structure. Check out &lt;a href=&#34;https://changelog.com/git-resources-for-visual-learners/&#34;&gt;these resources for visual learners&lt;/a&gt;. A couple of the demos are really useful for demonstrating visually what happens when you issue a command.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a quick read, check out this simple introduction &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@dfosco/git-for-designers-856c434716e#.p6q05e1mr&#34;&gt;Git for Designers&lt;/a&gt; on medium. While you are more likely to see GitHub projects geared around code, here a couple of resources geared specifically for journalists and designers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://knightlab.northwestern.edu/2013/06/13/getting-github-why-journalists-should-know-and-use-the-social-coding-site/&#34;&gt;Why journalists should know and use GitHub&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://venturebeat.com/2014/06/05/for-designers-version-control-is-a-big-problem-but-github-is-close-to-solving-it/&#34;&gt;GitHub for designers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>